cartoonnetworkya.com 2013-06-24

# Privacy Policy | Cartoon Network

Thank you for visiting Cartoon Network. Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, and to help ensure a rewarding online experience for all visitors, we provide this Privacy Statement summarizing our online information practices and explaining the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used. This Privacy Statement, where posted, applies to our information practices on Cartoon Network's Web sites (the "Sites") and for products and services we make available on various mobile devices or other platforms ("Apps"). This Privacy Statement does not apply to any other information collected by Cartoon Network and its affiliated entities through any other means. Cartoon Network and its affiliated entities are collectively referred to in this Privacy Statement as "Cartoon Network," "we" or "us."

Cartoon Network is committed to providing fun, safe and secure Sites and Apps for people of all ages. We are dedicated to safeguarding all personal information collected online and to helping our visitors learn how to exercise control over personal information while exploring the Internet. Because many visitors to the Sites are children, we make efforts to ensure that children access only the content that is appropriate for them. In addition, we employ special measures to help children protect their privacy while online. We do not ask children to disclose more personal information than is necessary for them to participate in a particular activity, and we take steps to prevent children from posting contact information.

As we continue to offer our visitors new and different types of content and services, we may modify our practices from time to time.

**I. The Information We Collect**

**Our Sites**

At Cartoon Network, we do not collect personally identifiable information on our Sites unless our visitors voluntarily provide it to us when you visit our Sites, including when you participate in activities on our Sites like sweepstakes, contests, games, informational and promotional offers, message boards, chat rooms, profile pages, social community environments, or other public forums, and when you provide information to our customer service representatives. For some activities, such as online polls or surveys, we may ask visitors to provide information that is not personally identifiable. This might include first name only, city or state of residence, age, gender, or a favorite cartoon character. For some other activities, such as entering sweepstakes and subscribing to our e-mail newsletters, we may ask visitors to provide a first name and e-mail address. For other activities, such as sending an electronic postcard or e-mail to a friend, we may also ask for personal information about other people. This is usually limited to a first name and e-mail address. E-mail addresses collected to send an electronic postcard or e-mail to a friend are deleted immediately when the requested postcard or e-mail is transmitted. For some limited activities, campaigns, or offers, intended for parents and adults, we may ask a parent or adult to provide their name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, fax number, credit card information, cable or satellite provider, and/or information about their interests in and use of various products, programs, and services. In order to provide appropriate customer service support for some features of our Sites or improve our products, we may ask visitors to provide a first name, email address and limited information that is relevant to a customer service inquiry.

Visitors who order merchandise or other materials from the Sites or participate in certain interactive features will be required to provide their full name, billing and mailing addresses, e-mail address, telephone number and a credit card number. If an order is being shipped to a third party, we will also need the recipient's name and mailing address. Before collecting information in connection with an e-commerce order, we will verify the validity of the purchaser's credit card. On occasion, we might solicit additional voluntary information regarding shoppers' personal shopping preferences.

When a child under age thirteen participates in another ongoing activity on a Site that requires the collection, retention, and use of personal information, we will also ask for a parent's e-mail address so that we can notify the parent that we have received personal information from their child. We do not knowingly collect names and e-mail addresses from children under age thirteen for these types of activities without notifying the parent via e-mail and giving the parent the option to remove their child's e-mail address from the applicable database for that activity. For specific one-time requests we receive from visitors on Sites, e-mail addresses are collected and used only in connection with the specific one-time request. For example, for sweepstakes and contests, e-mail addresses are collected for the purpose of entering the online sweepstakes or contest on a one-time basis and are used to notify winners of the sweepstakes or contest once by e-mail. Winners will be required to return a completed prize acceptance form contained in the notification e-mail by facsimile or U.S. mail within a designated time period (along with the signature of a parent or legal guardian for all minors).

In connection with registration for certain interactive online games or features on the Sites, we may ask users to provide certain information that is not personally identifiable such as city or state of residence, date of birth and gender. For children under the age of thirteen, we will ask for the child's e-mail address, which will not be stored in a retrievable form but instead using a "hash" or unique code generated from the e-mail address that will allow us on a one-time basis, for example, to respond to an inquiry from the child regarding a lost user name or password. We also may ask for a parental email address for children under age 13 who register in order to provide notice to the parent that his or her child would like to participate in registration for certain interactive features. For individuals age thirteen and over, we may collect and store an e-mail address to use in the case of forgotten passwords and to send newsletters and/or marketing information for which the individual has consented. 

When visitors come to our Sites, we also may collect some non-personally identifiable information such as the current Internet protocol address and the type of computer operating system you are using (e.g., Microsoft Windows or Mac OS), the type of browser you are using (e.g., Firefox, Internet Explorer), the domain name of the Internet service provider (e.g., America Online, Earthlink), your activities while visiting our Sites, your activities while playing games or utilizing services on our Sites (e.g., which of our Web pages you viewed or which games you played), and the advertisements you have been shown.

**Our Apps**

Our Apps generally include features, functionality and content such as games, videos, and activities. Cartoon Network does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13 in our Apps. The data collected in an App may vary by App but will include any information a user provides once the user downloads and uses the App. For example, some of our Apps may require you to first register and create an account with us (e.g. user name, password, or email address) before you can use it. Other Apps may require additional information from you, such as transaction-related information (e.g. when you make purchases, respond to any offers) We may also use information you provide us to reach you when you contact us for help. If you interact with third-party social media sites and applications, we may have access to certain information from your social media account such as your user name, profile picture, information about friends and followers, and content posted or viewed through the social media. When you use social media networking platforms and plugins, you share your information with them and their use of the information will be subject to that social media site’s privacy practices. To help improve the design, functionality, performance, and content of our Apps, we usually collect certain information when you use the App on your mobile device, such as usage, viewing and technical data including the type of mobile device you use, your unique device ID, your device’s IP address, your mobile operator and operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use the App. Our Apps usually do not collect precise information about the location of your mobile device, and only would do so if you are specifically prompted to provide your consent to do so. You can always manage your location preferences at any time by adjusting the settings on your device. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided Cartoon Network with any personally identifiable information through an App without consent, please contact us at advanced.platforms@turner.com so we can delete such information.

**II. How We Use the Information**

We use visitors' personal information collected in connection with child-directed activities for internal purposes only, such as enabling visitors to enter our online contests or sweepstakes, to subscribe to an online newsletter, to provide customer service, and/or for the purposes for which you provided the information. We may also use personal information provided by shoppers at a Site such as Shop.CartoonNetwork.com or by parents or adults in other sections of our Sites to send them, by e-mail or direct mail, notification of special offers, sale events, or birthday reminders. These notifications are sent only to those visitors to the Sites who ask to receive them. For some limited activities directed to parents or adults such as offers related to our pro-social initiatives like Stop Bullying: Speak Up or the availability of the Boomerang network in your area, we may disclose personally identifiable information to third parties whose practices are not covered by this Privacy Statement (e.g., local cable affiliates, non-profit organizations) that want to contact you in connection with other initiatives or marketing products or services to you. If a Site shares a parent's or adult's personally identifiable information with such third parties, it will provide the parent or adult with notice or an opportunity to opt out or block such uses.

We use parents' e-mail addresses to notify them when we have received personal information on Sites such as e-mail addresses from their children and to give parents the option to remove their child's name from our lists. We use information we collect about others only to enable visitors to our Site to communicate with those other people, for example, by sending them electronic greeting cards or e-mail or to ship gifts purchased on Shop.CartoonNetwork.com.

We do not keep any personal information we obtain through a contest or sweepstakes until we have successfully selected a winner(s), awarded the prize(s), and administered the contest or sweepstakes. We only use the e-mail addresses of subscribers to our Sites' e-mail newsletters to send them the requested newsletter(s). Each newsletter also includes instructions for subscription removal via return e-mail.

We never sell, rent, or otherwise share our visitors' personal information with third parties without appropriate notice and consent. Sometimes, we use agents or contractors to provide services to our visitors, such as helping us conduct a sweepstakes, sending prizes to winners, shipping customer orders made on the Sites, or providing customer service related to activities on the Sites. In these cases, we require the agent or contractor to keep the information confidential and to use it only for the specific services they are performing. We may on occasion combine information we collect through our Sites with information that we collect from other sources. We sometimes use non-personally identifiable information that we collect to improve the design and content of our Sites, and to improve our visitors' experience on the Sites. We also may aggregate, use and share this information with third parties to analyze Site usage, as well as to offer products, programs, or services.

We may disclose personally identifiable information in response to legal process, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. We also may use and disclose such information in response to a law enforcement agency's request, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violations of our terms of use, to verify or enforce compliance with the policies governing our Sites and Apps and applicable laws, or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements. In addition, we may transfer personally identifiable information about you if we or one of our business units are acquired by, sold to, or merged with another entity.

We will not use or transfer personally identifiable information in ways that are materially different from the ones described above without also providing parental notification of such practices and obtaining consent for any materially different uses.

**III. Cookies and Web Beacons**

To enhance your online experience, our Sites use a software technology called "cookies" or similar technologies. Cookies are small text files placed in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. Cookies do not contain any personally identifiable information. Although cookies could enable us to relate a visitor's use of our Sites and the Internet to personal information that the visitor has provided, such as an e-mail address, we do not use cookies in connection with personal information with one exception: for some activities, we use session cookies to ensure that visitors under the age of 13 provide a parental email address to assist with our compliance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act. We do use cookies to determine how many visitors we have and how often they visit various sections of our Sites and to improve or customize the content, offerings and/or advertisements on our Sites. For example, we may use cookies to personalize your experience at our Sites (e.g., to recognize you by your user name when you return to a Site), and to enable use of shopping carts on our Sites.

We, our third party service providers and/or our partners also may use cookies to manage and measure the performance of advertisements displayed on or delivered by or through the Sites and Apps. This also helps us, our service providers and partners provide more relevant advertising. For more information regarding third-party ad servers, see "Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites," below.

"Web beacons" or clear .gifs or similar technologies are small pieces of code placed on a web page to monitor the behavior and collect data about the visitors viewing a web page. For example, web beacons can be used to count the users who visit a web page or to deliver a cookie to the browser of a visitor viewing that page. We, our third party service providers and/or our partners may use web beacons on our Sites or Apps from time to time for this and other purposes.

You can change your privacy preferences regarding the use of cookies and similar technologies through your browser. You may set your browser to accept all cookies, block certain cookies, require your consent before a cookie is placed in your browser, or block all cookies. Blocking all cookies will affect your online experience and may prevent you from enjoying the full features offered at our Sites. Please consult the "Help" section of your browser for more information.

**IV. Collection of Information by Third-Party Sites, Ad Servers and Sponsors**

Our Sites and Apps contain links to other Web sites, including those of sponsors and advertisers, whose information practices may be different from ours. Sometimes these third party Web sites might conduct contests or sweepstakes that are promoted on our Sites. Visitors should consult those other third party Web sites' privacy notices, since those Web sites are not covered by our Privacy Statement and may follow different procedures.

Additionally, we and our advertisers may use third parties to serve or present the ads that appear on our Site and Apps and to conduct research about the advertisements. These third parties may view, edit or set their own cookies. We, our third party service providers and/or partners may also place cookies, web beacons, clear .gifs or similar technologies and collect data to help present such advertisements on our Sites and our Apps, and to help measure and research the advertisements' effectiveness. The use of these technologies by these third parties is subject to their own privacy policies and is not covered by our Privacy Statement. For more information about third-party ad servers and your ability to opt-out of targeted advertising from such third party ad servers generally, please see http://www.networkadvertising.org/.

**V. International Transfer**

Cartoon Network operates globally so it may be necessary to transfer any information provided to these Sites or Apps internationally. In particular, the information provided will likely be transferred to and processed in the United States where many of our central databases operate. The data protection and other laws of other countries, such as the United States, may not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using this Site, you consent to your information being collected and used as set forth in this Privacy Statement.

**VI. Security**

We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures in an effort to safeguard and help prevent unauthorized access, maintain data security, and correctly use the information we collect online.

We are particularly sensitive to visitors' security concerns regarding the use of credit cards to purchase products over the Internet. For orders placed on our Sites, we use a technology that automatically encrypts credit card data while information is being transmitted over the Internet, provided that the visitor's browser supports the Secure Socket Layer protocol (SSL).

To verify the security of your connection at our Sites, check the lower left corner of your browser window after accessing the server. If you see an unbroken or a closed lock, then SSL is active and the server is secure. You may also check by looking at the URL line of your browser. When accessing a secure server, the site address will change from http to https.

**VII. Access and Choice**

For information collected on our Sites, visitors and their parents can send a letter or postcard to our Cartoon Network Privacy Manager at the mailing address provided below to:

  * access personally identifiable information that a Site has collected online from you or your child,
  * correct factual errors in such information, 
  * request to have this information deleted, or 
  * request that we no longer collect or maintain such information.

Please be sure to include your e-mail address and a telephone number where we can reach you. To protect our visitors’ privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access to the personal information that we collect and maintain about you or your child.

For information collected on our Apps, you can stop all collection of information by the App easily by uninstalling it from your device. You may use the standard uninstall processes as may be available as part of your mobile device or via the mobile application marketplace or network. If you would like to opt out and stop receiving marketing communications from us, you may follow the "unsubscribe" instructions provided in any marketing email or for mobile device push notifications, you can manage your preferences either through your device or App settings depending on the type of device. If you’d like us to correct, update your information, or help you opt out from our marketing communications and/or delete user provided data that you have provided via the App, please contact us at advanced.platforms@turner.com and we will respond in a reasonable time. Please note that some or all of the user-provided data may be required in order for an App to function properly, and we may be required to retain certain information by law. To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections or deletions.

**VIII. Contact Us**

If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our Privacy Statement and/or practices, please contact us at the following e-mail address, mailing address and telephone number:

Email: [Privacy.CartoonNetwork@turner.com](mailto:Privacy.CartoonNetwork@turner.com)

Mailing Address (Postcards only, please):

Privacy Manager - Cartoon Network   
TEG Online   
1050 Techwood Drive  
Atlanta, GA 30318

404-878-0694

**IX. Updates & Effective Date**

From time to time, we may update this Privacy Statement. We will notify you about material changes in the way we treat personally identifiable information by placing a notice on our Sites. We encourage you to periodically check back and review this Privacy Statement so that you always will know what information we collect, how we use it, and to whom we disclose it.

The Privacy Statement posted on this Site was updated on or about August 6, 2012.

**X. A Final Note to Parents**

The Internet offers a world of opportunity for children. Your guidance and involvement are essential to help ensure that children have a safe and rewarding online experience. Your efforts to instill responsible information practices will help steer your children to age-appropriate sites, and will go a long way toward ensuring that your children have enriching experiences in content provided online, mobile or on other digital platforms or environments.
